<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ball on IGD301 - Blog</title>
    <link>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/tags/ball/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ball on IGD301 - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/tags/ball/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project Part 1</title>
      <link>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part1/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to start the project. As described previously in lab 3, I have chosen to implement the teleportation ball as my locomotion technique. Even if I know that this locomotion technique is not the most adapted for the parkour provided by the teachers I still chose to make my tests by using it.
The first step was to import the project. I didn&amp;rsquo;t encounter any problems, I simply followed the teacher&amp;rsquo;s tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Part 2</title>
      <link>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part2/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to get back to the project. As described in the previous post there are two major issues to address:
 The ball sometimes crosses the ground when it has a collider It is difficult to start the game. In fact, the user does not collide with the collider of the banner because of teleportation.  Today I will focus on the balls and leave the problem of starting the game for another time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Part 3</title>
      <link>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part3/</guid>
      <description>Today my goal is to solve the problems with the coins and banners and to add the bouncing ball. As a reminder, currently the balls collide with the coins. This is a problem because the coins are not supposed to be solid, and also because when you use the sticky ball you teleport onto the coin. Since the locomotion is done with the ball, I decided that the ball represents the movement of the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Part 4</title>
      <link>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lbertrand417.github.io/IGD301-blog/blog/project_part4/</guid>
      <description>Today I planned to correct the trigger problem (you can bring the ball back in your hand or change it even when the ball is thrown). For that, I added a boolean which is true when the ball is thrown and which blocks the AttachBall() and ChangeBall() functions.
I also tried to allow the user to change the hand. My idea is that each controller has a MySelect.cs script and that in LocomotionTechnique we disable/enable one or the other depending on the user&amp;rsquo;s actions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
